XIAOYU A. GAO

13107 Meadow Hall Court, Herndon VA, 20171 | (703) 901-0568 | gao_xiaoyu@bah.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack Javascript Developer with a passion for technology and innovation. My experience and expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures using Agile development methodologies. In particular, I specialize in web technologies such as React/Redux, Node.js/Express, Docker, Terraform and AWS, as well as Blockchain development with Solidity and Truffle.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

- Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering
- Rodman Scholar (Honors Program for Top 5% of Engineers

Skills

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7), Shell (Bash), Java (7/8), C/C++

Front End Web Technologies and Design Tools:

 Sketch, HTML5, CSS3/4, React, Redux, PostCSS, Webpack

Blockchain Technologies:

• Ethereum, Geth, Solidity, Truffle

Development and Testing Tools:

• Agile (Scrum), Git, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, ESLint, NPM, Yarn

Back-End Web Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, Rollup, MySQL, MongoDB

Infrastructure/Automation Technologies:

• Docker, Travis, CircleCI, Terraform, Packer, AWS, Azure

Work Experience

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - Present

- Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application to replace existing transactions infrastructure.
- Front end built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form and styled with Spectre.css and custom CSS as a static SPA.
- Back end written in Node, is and data is persisted on Azure SQL Database, as well as on the Microsoft's Blockchain.
- Containerized the back end with Docker, and provisioned infrastructure with Terraform.
- SPA and API deployed on Azure Web Apps, and Geth nodes hosted on Microsoft's Blockchain as a Service.
- Application and API deployed on Azure Web Apps, and Geth nodes hosted on Microsoft's Blockchain as a Service.
- Architected the front end and back end, as well as the cloud infrasture for the project.
- Led development efforts across the stack, including the front end, back end, devops, in a small team of six developers in an Agile environment.

Capital One - Technology Development Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

- Developed a sprint tracking web application that aggregates data from various tools such as VersionOne, Git/SVN, Hudson/Jenkin and SonarCubed in an user-friendly and responsive dashboard interface.
- Aided in the design of the UX/UI and implemented front-end logic to display data to users as well as validate inputs using AngularJS, Jquery, SASS and custom CSS.
- Developed RESTful APIs to allow communication between front-end and back-end using Spring Core.
- Deployed application to an internally accessible AWS server.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Research Assistant Intern

May 2014 - August 2014

- Developed an email filtration IDS web application for detecting malicious email content.
- Application performed full packet capture of SMTP traffic and static analysis of email pcaps and links using Bro-IDS & MASTIFF.
- Designed front-end interface using Jquery and Bootstrap and developed the back-end with Flask and SQLAlchemy.
- Application used to collect metrics on email traffic to improve incident response time for internal cyber security team.

Select Projects

UVA Lambdas Website (github.com/UVA-Lambdas)

- The official home page of Lambda Phi Epsilon, Alpha Tau Chapter, at the University of Virginia.
- Designed in Sketch, written as an SPA with React and styled with CSS4 using PostCSS and CSSNext.
- Automated deployment to Github pages using Travis for CI/CD.